# MELVYN THOMAS WILLIAM LING

MELVYN.LING@GMAIL.COM | 289 788 2149 | HAMILTON, ONTARIO L8L 2L6
LINKEDIN.CA/MELVYN-LING | GITHUB.COM/MELVYNLING | MELVYNLING.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

## **SUMMARY**

A front-end web developer whose creative flair and adaptive nature strike the balance between form and function. As a recent graduate of the University of Toronto's School of Continuing Studies Web Development program, a strong command of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Node.js amongst other techs and frameworks has been established. He uses his diverse experience, spanning political science, customer service, and the sheet metal trade, to optimise and contextualise his projects to best serve their target demographics.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- Node.js
- MERN Stack
- Version Control (GitHub)

- JavaScript
- React.js

- API/AJAX
- MySQL/MongoDB

- JQuery
- Handlebars.js
- Firebase
- Heroku

# **PROJECTS**

cryptoTRKR Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/cryptoTRKR cryptotrkr.herokuapp.com

• This app allows the user to see the historical data of the users favourite 4 cryptocurrencies. This is a serverless react app that stores the user's selection in the localstorage in their browser. It also utilizes React Context API to make the API calls to the CryptoCompare API.

**Technology used:** CSS, HTML, JavaScript, NodeJS, Lodash, MomentsJS, highchartsJS, CryptoCompare API, React, local storage

BitCoin Value Tracker Team Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/bitCoinValueTracker | gentle-spire-69297.herokuapp.com

• This application allows the users to see the historical trends of Bitcoin by seeing their entry and exit points for potential investments. I was responsible for the API call, the math and logic involved with calculating the rates, as well as the front-end overall appearance.

Technology used: HTML, CSS, J, NodeJS, MomentsJS, handlebarsJS, coindesk API, Materialize UI.

Train Scheduler Lead Developer

github.com/MelvynLing/trainscheduler | melvynling.github.io/trainscheduler

• This app allows the user to document and create a train schedule, allowing them to see when their trains arrivals and departures. This is a serverless application -- it utilizes google Firebase to store the user's inputs instead of a standard database.

Technology used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Bootstrap

World Cup Trivia Game Lead Developer

aithub.com/MelvynLing/TriviaGame | melvynling.github.io/TriviaGame

• This app uses Javascript and jQuery to interactively test the user's world cup knowledge. It demonstrates strong Javascript skills, as it makes use of setTimeout, setInterval, and a few other javascript methods.

Technology used: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Customer Service Representative**

May 2016 – December 2018

OSG Canada Inc.

Burlington, ON

- Responsible for running various sales reports and account for any anomalies that may have occurred in the buying and selling of OSG products, demonstrating key analytical skills.
- Assisted in the coordination of the first tool dispensing system at a larger local customer, where users would input their requested tools and receive them if stocked.

**Operations Assistant** 

(Intermittently) April 2012 – Present

Alco Sheet Metal Ltd.

Hamilton, ON

- Supported managers, tradespeople, and others in the daily operations of the company, assisting with data entry and computer related activities, as well as in the tool shop and on various jobsites.
- Facilitated training for two colleagues on new computer programs and operating systems, advised in the selection of programs.

## Automobile Claims Adjuster/Disposition Adjuster

*Sept 2014 – Oct 2015* 

Aviva Canada Inc

Hamilton, ON

- Worked as a front-line agent to set up automobile insurance claims for customers who had been involved in an automobile accident.
- Selected to take part in a third-party report team, calling out on customers who were reported to be involved in an automobile incident to investigate potential automobile claims.

# **EDUCATION**

School of Continuing Studies, Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp.

December 2018

- Toronto, Ontario

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Arts (Honours), Political Science.

April 2012

- Hamilton, Ontario

McMaster University